https://company.cdn.overdrive.com/policies/privacy-policy.htm

Borrow eBooks, audiobooks, and videos from thousands of public libraries worldwide.
OverDrive Privacy Policy
OverDrive, Inc. and its affiliates ("OverDrive", "we", "us" or "our") provides digital content, applications,
technology, services, and hosted websites to third parties. This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices
for all OverDrive-hosted websites, software, technologies, services, support services, applications including
Libby, Sora, and the OverDrive app, and OverDrive accounts (collectively referred to as "Services").
OverDrive respects your privacy. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to make you aware of how OverDrive collects,
manages, protects, uses, and/or shares information and what choices are available to you regarding the collection,
use and distribution of your Personal Information and non-personally identifiable information ("non-PII").
Many users under the age of 13 enjoy using the Services. To see OverDrive's policy regarding the collection of
information from children who are under 13 years old, please click here
for OverDrive's Privacy Policy for Children.
What is Personal Information and non-PII?
Generally, "Personal Information" is information that can be used on its own to identify a specific person.
For example,
Personal Information can be a full name, home address, email address, phone number, or login details. In most
cases, non-personally identifiable information or "non-PII" is data that cannot be used on its own to identify a specific person.
For example, in the context of the Services, non-PII can be language preference, bookmarks, or highlights.
Non-PII is treated by OverDrive as Personal Information when it's collected on an individual level and linked to any
Personal Information that you have chosen to submit to OverDrive or that OverDrive may have collected from your interactions
with the Services.
What information do I need to submit to OverDrive in order to use the Services?
You can use most Services without submitting much information to OverDrive.
A valid library card or school ID is all you need to use most Services.
An OverDrive account is not required to use most library Services. If you choose to create an OverDrive account,
you will be required to submit Personal Information to OverDrive. Please click here to visit the section of
this Privacy Policy that applies specifically to your OverDrive account.
As part of your interaction with the Services, you may willingly submit your Personal Information in order to
access certain features, such as submitting your email address in order to place a hold on a digital content title.
What information does OverDrive collect?
In addition to information that you may willingly submit to OverDrive, such as your library card number, school
ID number, and/or email address, OverDrive may collect and store certain Personal Information and non-PII
related to your interactions and use of our Services, including but not limited to, IP address, device type,
device ID, operating system, library card number, Adobe ID, library name, lending history, holds, reading
progress, bookmarks, highlights, notes, and online activity.
Some Services provide the ability for you to see your lending history. If you are using your institution’s
OverDrive-hosted website, Libby, or the OverDrive app, you will have the option to show your lending history.
You can hide your lending history by following the instructions within the app or help articles.
Your lending
history is protected by OverDrive as confidential. It is not shared with any third parties, except to staff
with appropriate authority acting within the scope of their duties for the administration of your institution
(library, school, etc.).
If we are compelled to disclose your lending history pursuant to a court order or
subpoena, or to a person or agency with the relevant administrative or legislative investigative power, we
will seek to challenge and limit the scope and comply with the authorized agency or person only as required by law.
How does OverDrive protect my information?
OverDrive takes information security very seriously. We have implemented measures to protect against the loss, misuse,
and alteration of your information. Your information is protected by physical, electronic, and procedural
safeguards to prevent unauthorized disclosure. We encrypt the transmission of information using secure sockets layer
(SSL) technology. We use computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption and physical access controls to our
buildings and files. We authorize access to Personal Information only for those employees who require it to fulfill their
job responsibilities.
How does OverDrive use information?
We collect information from you in order to:
Determine your current geographic location and/or language so that we may provide localized content and Services;
Comply with the requirements of our publisher, library, and retail partners;
Alert you of opportunities to renew loans, return loans, checkout digital content on which you’ve placed a hold, and cancel holds;
Provide recommendations for digital content we think you may enjoy;
Notify you of opportunities to provide feedback for OverDrive's Services;
Sync bookmarks and most recent point viewed/played across devices;
Support the internal operations of the Services, including but not limited to support for: activities necessary
to maintain or analyze the Services, network communications, user authentication or personalization
of content, activities necessary to perform authorized school or educational purposes, and security of users;
Integrate with additional service providers for use of the Services;
Personalize our Services to better reflect particular interests and preferences and in certain instances for remarketing; and
Generally improve your experience.
OverDrive never sells your Personal Information or non-PII. OverDrive will not use your information for any purposes other than the specified use.
Email addresses submitted to OverDrive for holds notifications are stored by OverDrive so you can place future holds in a quicker, more convenient
manner. OverDrive will not use your email address to send you any marketing or promotional communications without your opt-in consent.
We may anonymize certain Personal Information and share it in an aggregated form with third parties in order to
analyze Service usage, improve the Service, or for other similar purposes. Such information is anonymous and cannot
be used to identify you. The use and disclosure of such anonymous information is not subject to any restrictions
under this Privacy Policy.
How long is information retained by OverDrive?
We retain information for as long as OverDrive deems necessary to provide the Services or as otherwise permitted by
applicable law. Information about users of school Services is only retained by OverDrive for the time period
necessary to support the authorized school or educational purposes.
Does OverDrive use cookies and similar technologies?
Yes, we use cookies and similar technologies to collect and store certain information when you use, access, or interact
with the Services. Cookies are small data file identifiers that are transferred to your device or web browser that
allow us to recognize your device or web browser when you visit or use the Service.
We use cookies for many purposes,
such as to support the internal operations of the Services and make improvements to the Services.
To read more about
cookies and similar technologies, please visit our Cookie Policy.
What if I share Information with others while using the Services?
While using our Services, you may enjoy opportunities to post reviews, rate digital content, and share digital
content information with others in public forums and on social networking websites such as Facebook, Twitter,
and Goodreads. When you share such information, it is made public and is not subject to this Privacy Policy.
We are not responsible for any third party's use of information you publicly display or disclose through
our Services.
What happens when I visit an external website not related to OverDrive's Services?
Our Services may include links to non-OverDrive websites, outside the control of OverDrive. If you click these
links, you will leave OverDrive and enter websites that may have different privacy policies than OverDrive.
OverDrive is not responsible for the information handling practices of these other websites. These linked
websites have separate and independent privacy statements, notices and terms of use, which we recommend you
read carefully.
Is my information transmitted to other countries?
Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process information necessarily
involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Therefore, by using the Services, you acknowledge
and consent to the transfer of your information outside your country of residence to any country where we
have facilities or engage third parties (including but not limited to, payment processors, cloud service
or other Information Technology providers, and other companies that provide services to us). If you are visiting the Services from the EU,
please click here to visit the section of this Privacy Policy that applies to transfers from the EU to the US.
You understand that the countries to which we may transfer information may not have as comprehensive a level of data protection
as in your country.
OverDrive requires that third parties (if any), such as cloud service providers, with whom
information about users of school Services is shared are obligated to safeguard such information using policies
and procedures that are consistent with this Privacy Policy and must only use the information in order to perform
the authorized school or educational purpose for which it was provided.
What if I contact OverDrive for a support issue?
If you contact OverDrive directly for assistance resolving an issue with the Services, it may be necessary for
OverDrive to use support tools to resolve your issue. For a limited number of issues, these tools may provide
OverDrive support personnel with visibility of your borrowing information while your support case is being
resolved.
What is required to create an OverDrive account?
Your name, email address, and password are required to create an OverDrive account. By creating and using an OverDrive account and/or otherwise consenting to the sharing of information with us, you authorize OverDrive to collect and retain the Personal Information submitted by you. You also affirm that you are at least 13 years of age and acknowledge that an OverDrive account is not intended for use by individuals under 13 years of age. You may not share your information regarding your OverDrive account, including but not limited to your login credentials such as your password.
How can I change my preferences?
You can change your preferences for receiving newsletters, promotional offers, product updates and other OverDrive-initiated
communications by emailing privacy@overdrive.com.
What is OverDrive's Instant Digital Card service?
OverDrive's Instant Digital Card online service ("IDC") helps users obtain access to the library's OverDrive digital collection.
Only authorized patrons of the library are permitted to access and checkout digital content from the library's digital collection.
You must be at least 13 years old to use IDC.
For users of libraries located in the U.S.:
If your library is located in the U.S. and you use IDC, you will be asked to submit your name, mobile phone number, and email
address to OverDrive.
Only U.S. mobile phone numbers are eligible for use with IDC.
Your name and mobile phone number
will be used
to confirm your mobile phone number is associated with you and to verify that you have an address in your library's service area.
U.S. libraries that participate in IDC provide OverDrive with the zip codes that comprise their service area.
Submitting your name, mobile
phone number, and email address to IDC confirms your consent to this Privacy Policy and OverDrive's
Terms and Conditions.
To verify that your address is in your library's service area, OverDrive will share your name and mobile phone number with a third-party verification service,
Cognito.
Cognito will use your name and mobile phone number to return an address, if any, to OverDrive.
Cognito does not use your name or mobile phone number for marketing or sales purposes, nor do they share your name or mobile phone number with third parties for marketing or sales purposes.
OverDrive will send a text message to the mobile phone number you provide (standard text message rates apply)
to verify the mobile phone number's association with you.
If you are validated as having a residential address within your library’s service area, your mobile phone number will serve as your digital library card and you will be able to access and checkout digital content from your library’s OverDrive digital collection.
Your name, mobile phone number, and address are stored by OverDrive for the purpose of authenticating your checkouts from the library’s OverDrive digital collection.
Unless otherwise permitted through your opt-in consent to receive marketing communications, OverDrive does not use your name or mobile phone number for marketing or sales purposes, nor do we share your name or mobile phone number with third parties for marketing or sales purposes.
In addition to obtaining checkout privileges to your library's digital collection, you may also be eligible for a library card for access to your library's
additional resources (e.g., physical book and media borrowing).
Through the validation process, OverDrive will store your address for the purpose of
providing your name, address, mobile phone number, and email address (if provided by you) to your library, where you may be eligible for a library card for access to additional
library resources.
Your use of IDC confirms your consent to OverDrive providing your name, address, mobile phone number, and email address (if provided by you) with your
library, and confirms your consent to be contacted by your library, if necessary.
If you have questions or concerns regarding IDC, please contact OverDrive at privacy@overdrive.com.
For users of libraries located outside of the U.S.:
If your library is located outside of the U.S. and you use IDC, you will be asked to submit your name, mobile phone number, and a country code
or campaign code (“Code”).
The Code you submit will be used to verify that you have a valid Code to be granted access to your library’s
OverDrive digital collection.
Submitting a Code to IDC confirms your consent to this Privacy Policy and OverDrive’s Terms and Conditions.
If your Code is validated by IDC, your mobile phone number will serve as your digital library card and you will be able to access and
checkout digital content from your library’s OverDrive digital collection.
Your name and mobile phone number are stored by OverDrive
for the purpose of authenticating your checkouts from the library’s OverDrive digital collection.
Unless otherwise permitted through your
opt-in consent to receive marketing communications, OverDrive does not use your name or mobile phone number for marketing or sales purposes,
nor do we share your name or mobile phone number with third parties for marketing or sales purposes.
In addition to obtaining checkout privileges to your library’s digital collection, you may also be eligible for a library card for
access to your library’s additional resources (e.g., physical book and media borrowing).
OverDrive may provide your name, mobile phone
number, and email address (if provided by you) to your library, where you may be eligible for a library card for access to additional
library resources.
Your use of IDC confirms your consent to OverDrive providing your name, mobile phone number, and email address
(if provided by you) with your library, and confirms your consent to be contacted by your library, if necessary.
If you have questions or concerns regarding IDC, please contact OverDrive at privacy@overdrive.com.
Rights applicable to users located in the EU
Data Transfer. OverDrive has adopted Standard Contractual Clauses (SCCs) to safeguard international data transfers, including
transfers of Personal Information from the EU, Switzerland, and the UK, to the US.
Legal basis for processing your Personal Information. If you are visiting a Service from the EU,
we must have a legal basis to process your Personal Information.
There are different legal bases on which we rely to process your Personal Information, namely:
Performance of a contract. The use of your Personal Information may be necessary to perform the specified function
for which you submit your Personal Information, and/or perform other contractual obligations and policies under which we provide our Services to you;
Consent. We will rely on your consent to use your information for direct marketing purposes.
You may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us using the information at the end of this Privacy Policy
or by following an unsubscribe link in any marketing communication you receive from us; and
Legitimate interests. We use your Personal Information for our legitimate interests to improve our Services,
for internal administration, and security purposes. In such circumstances, it is important for us to ensure that your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms are not overridden
by our legitimate interests.
Your choices under EU law. If you are visiting from the EU, you may email
privacy@overdrive.com or visit the Data Request center to ask us to:
See what Personal Information we hold about you
Modify or correct the Personal Information we hold about you
Object to our use of your Personal Information
Erase your Personal Information
Receive/Port your Personal Information in a usable electronic format
If contacting us does not resolve your issue, you have the right to make a complaint to your data protection authority (if one exists in your country).
If you are not subject to EU law, these rights do not apply to you.
Rights applicable to California residents
As explained in this Privacy Policy, OverDrive may collect certain information related to your interactions and use of our Services.
Information we collect directly from you. Depending on your use of the Services, the categories of information we may collect directly from you include the following:
Identifiers, such as your name, email address, library card number, and phone number (only for users of IDC);
We may also collect information you provide in your communications to us, such as when you respond to polls or surveys, or contact
us with a question, comment, or request.
Information we automatically collect from you. As you interact with the Services, we may also collect information about you
automatically though the use of cookies and similar technologies. Depending on your use of the Services, the categories of
information we automatically collect from you may include the following:
Identifiers, such as IP Address, Adobe ID, Cookie ID, and device ID.
Internet or other electronic network activity information, such as device type,
operating system, browsing history on OverDrive-hosted webpages, and information
related to your interaction with the Services, such as lending history, holds,
and reading progress.
If you do not want OverDrive-hosted websites to collect information through the use of cookies, you can set your web browser
to block cookies. Additionally, you can manage your cookie preferences through the "Cookie Settings" link located within
the Service. Please see our Cookie Policy for more information.
Information selling, sharing, and disclosing. OverDrive does not sell your information. OverDrive does not share your
information with third parties for money or other valuable consideration. OverDrive may disclose your information to
service providers solely for business purposes. These service providers support the internal operations of the Services,
assist OverDrive in providing you access to the Services, and assist OverDrive in monitoring, analyzing, and optimizing
the Services. The following categories of information may be disclosed to service providers for business purposes:
identifiers and internet or other electronic network activity information.
Your rights under applicable law. If you are a California resident, you or your authorized agent may email privacy@overdrive.com,
call toll-free 866-269-5794, or visit the Data Request center to ask us to:
See what Personal Information we hold about you
Modify or correct the Personal Information we hold about you
Delete your Personal Information
Receive/Port your Personal Information in a usable electronic format
Users may freely exercise these rights without fear of being denied the Services.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy was last updated in October 2020.
We will continue to evaluate this Privacy Policy against new technologies, business practices, and our users’ needs, and may make changes to the Privacy Policy accordingly. Please check the Privacy Policy periodically for updates. Your continued use of the Services after the posting of any changes to this Privacy Policy means that you agree to be bound by such changes.
In the event of a change of control (i.e. sale of sale or merger of OverDrive, Inc.) the successor entity will be subject to these same privacy commitments.
If we make material changes this Privacy Policy that increase our rights to use your Personal Information, we will
notify you via a prominent notice on the Services or via email prior to the change becoming effective. If you do
not agree to the changes, you should discontinue use of the Services.
Contact OverDrive
Please contact OverDrive at privacy@overdrive.com if:
You have any questions about this Privacy Policy;
You are not located in the EU or are not a California resident and you would like to request access to the Personal
Information we hold about you, or request the deletion of your Personal Information (alternatively, you may visit
the Data Request center);
You are a parent and want to inquire if your child has submitted Personal Information to OverDrive and to request
the review, correction, and/or removal of any such Personal Information from our system; or
You are a teacher or administrator at an educational institution using the school Services and want to request
the review, correction, and/or removal of a student’s Personal Information
